<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Compliance on Azure Crew</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/categories/compliance/</link><description>Recent content in Compliance on Azure Crew</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecrew.github.io/categories/compliance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data encryption and/or anonymization at ingestion (handling sensitive client/business data)</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-31-data-encryption-copy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-31-data-encryption-copy/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, data privacy and security are of paramount importance. As companies collect and store vast amounts of data, they must also take measures to protect sensitive client and business information. Data encryption and anonymization at ingestion are two essential techniques that organizations can use to ensure data privacy.
Data encryption involves converting plain text data into an encoded format, which can only be accessed through a secret key. This technique ensures that even if the data is intercepted, it cannot be read without the encryption key. Encryption can be applied to various types of data, including emails, files, and databases.</description></item><item><title>What it means to be compliant (SOC2, ISO27001, FIPS-X, etc.)</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-02-compliance-101/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-02-compliance-101/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, data security and privacy are paramount concerns for businesses and organizations of all sizes. Cyberattacks, data breaches, and other security incidents can cause significant financial losses, damage to reputation, and legal liabilities. To mitigate these risks, companies are increasingly seeking compliance with various industry-standard frameworks and regulations, such as SOC2, ISO27001, FIPS-X, and others. In this blog, we will discuss what it means to be compliant with these frameworks and regulations and why it is essential for businesses to strive for compliance.
SOC2 SOC2, which stands for Service Organization Control 2, is a set of auditing standards developed by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA) to evaluate the security, availability, processing integrity, confidentiality, and privacy of cloud-based services.</description></item></channel></rss>