<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure Crew</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Azure Crew</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecrew.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bobby Oustapassidis</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/about/boustaps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/about/boustaps/</guid><description>CEO/Founder</description></item><item><title>Nicolas Sao</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/about/nsao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/about/nsao/</guid><description>Cloud Security Architect</description></item><item><title>Jon Zlotnik</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/about/jzlotnik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/about/jzlotnik/</guid><description>DevSecOps Consultant</description></item><item><title>Data encryption and/or anonymization at ingestion (handling sensitive client/business data)</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-31-data-encryption-copy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-31-data-encryption-copy/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, data privacy and security are of paramount importance. As companies collect and store vast amounts of data, they must also take measures to protect sensitive client and business information. Data encryption and anonymization at ingestion are two essential techniques that organizations can use to ensure data privacy.
Data encryption involves converting plain text data into an encoded format, which can only be accessed through a secret key. This technique ensures that even if the data is intercepted, it cannot be read without the encryption key. Encryption can be applied to various types of data, including emails, files, and databases.</description></item><item><title>Writeups - Pentester Land</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-03-writeups-pentester-land/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-03-writeups-pentester-land/</guid><description>Pentester Land is a popular cybersecurity blog that provides insights and resources for pentesters, security researchers, and cybersecurity professionals. The blog covers a wide range of topics, including vulnerability assessments, penetration testing, exploit development, and much more. In this blog post, we will focus on one particular aspect of Pentester Land - the Writeups section.
The Writeups section of Pentester Land is a treasure trove of information for anyone interested in cybersecurity. It is a collection of detailed walkthroughs and analyses of real-world cybersecurity challenges, ranging from CTFs (Capture The Flag) to bug bounty programs. The Writeups section is organized by challenge type, difficulty level, and platform, making it easy to find the content you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.</description></item><item><title>What it means to be compliant (SOC2, ISO27001, FIPS-X, etc.)</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-02-compliance-101/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-02-compliance-101/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, data security and privacy are paramount concerns for businesses and organizations of all sizes. Cyberattacks, data breaches, and other security incidents can cause significant financial losses, damage to reputation, and legal liabilities. To mitigate these risks, companies are increasingly seeking compliance with various industry-standard frameworks and regulations, such as SOC2, ISO27001, FIPS-X, and others. In this blog, we will discuss what it means to be compliant with these frameworks and regulations and why it is essential for businesses to strive for compliance.
SOC2 SOC2, which stands for Service Organization Control 2, is a set of auditing standards developed by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants (AICPA) to evaluate the security, availability, processing integrity, confidentiality, and privacy of cloud-based services.</description></item><item><title>SecOps: distribution, storage, and rotation of secrets at run time</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-01-secops-secret-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/blog/2023-05-01-secops-secret-management/</guid><description>In the world of cybersecurity, SecOps (Security Operations) is an approach that combines security and operations teams to secure the organization&amp;rsquo;s systems, data, and infrastructure. One of the key aspects of SecOps is managing secrets - sensitive information such as passwords, access keys, and certificates. In this blog, we will discuss the distribution, storage, and rotation of secrets at run time.
Distribution of Secrets In SecOps, secrets need to be distributed securely to the relevant systems and applications. The first step in the distribution process is to encrypt the secrets. This ensures that even if the secrets are intercepted during transmission, they cannot be read by unauthorized parties.</description></item><item><title>Azure Consulting</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/azure_consulting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/azure_consulting/</guid><description>Our Azure Consulting service is designed to help businesses leverage the full potential of Microsoft Azure. Our team of experts will work closely with you to understand your unique business requirements and objectives. We will provide tailored guidance and strategic advice to help you plan, design, and implement Azure solutions that align with your goals. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking to migrate existing applications to Azure, optimize your Azure environment, or explore new possibilities, our Azure Consulting service will provide you with the expertise and support you need.</description></item><item><title>Azure Hybrid or Cloud Migration</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/migration/</guid><description>With our Azure Hybrid and Cloud Migrations service, we simplify the process of moving your applications, data, and infrastructure to the cloud. Our team of migration specialists will assess your current environment, develop a comprehensive migration strategy, and execute a seamless transition to Azure. We ensure minimal disruption to your business operations while maximizing the benefits of cloud computing, such as scalability, cost-efficiency, and enhanced agility. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re considering a hybrid cloud approach or a full migration to the cloud, our service will help you navigate the complexities and unlock the full potential of Azure.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Monitoring</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/cloud_monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/cloud_monitoring/</guid><description>Our Cloud Monitoring service provides real-time visibility into the performance, availability, and security of your cloud infrastructure and applications. We leverage advanced monitoring tools and technologies to collect and analyze data from your Azure environment, enabling proactive identification and resolution of issues. Our monitoring service covers various aspects, including resource utilization, application performance, network health, and security incidents. With comprehensive monitoring, you can optimize your Azure resources, improve the user experience, and ensure the smooth operation of your business-critical systems.</description></item><item><title>Devops</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/devops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/devops/</guid><description>Our DevOps service enables organizations to streamline their software development and deployment processes on Azure. We help you adopt a collaborative approach, combining development and operations teams to drive faster innovation and deliver high-quality applications. Our experts will assist you in implementing DevOps practices, such as continuous integration, continuous delivery, and automated testing. By leveraging Azure DevOps tools and best practices, you can achieve faster time-to-market, improved software quality, and increased agility in responding to customer demands.</description></item><item><title>Endpoint Management</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/endpoints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/endpoints/</guid><description>Endpoint Management is a crucial aspect of maintaining a secure and efficient IT infrastructure. Our Endpoint Management service focuses on managing and securing all your devices, including desktops, laptops, mobile devices, and IoT endpoints, through the power of Azure. We help you centralize device management, enforce security policies, and ensure compliance across your entire organization. With features like device inventory, software deployment, patch management, and remote troubleshooting, our service empowers you to effectively manage and protect your endpoints, enhancing productivity and minimizing security risks.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure &amp; Security</title><link>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/infra_security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://azurecrew.github.io/services/infra_security/</guid><description>Our Infrastructure &amp;amp; Security service is designed to address the foundational elements of your Azure environment. We provide comprehensive infrastructure design, deployment, and management services tailored to your specific needs. Our team of experts will help you architect a robust and scalable Azure infrastructure, leveraging best practices and industry standards. Additionally, we prioritize security at every step, implementing advanced security controls, threat detection mechanisms, and compliance measures to protect your data and applications. With our Infrastructure &amp;amp; Security service, you can achieve a reliable, high-performance Azure environment while mitigating risks and ensuring data integrity.</description></item></channel></rss>